A Guide to the Papers of William B. Spong, 1965-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of William B. Spong, 1965-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9838
This collection consists of 291,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Stored off-site. Users must request boxes 48 hours in advance of desired use. Neither drop-in nor next-day requests can be fulfilled. For additional information, contact Special Collections.
Acquisition Information
This collection was originally loaned to the University of Virginia Library on December 15, 1972, by Senator William B. Spong, Jr., of Portsmouth, Virginia. The deposit was changed to a gift on November 17, 1988.
Biographical/Historical Information
Who's Who in America, 47 edition, 1992-1993, p. 3195, Vol. 2, L-Z. See also the guide to 9838-b for additional information about Senator Spong.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. 291,000 items (194 cubic boxes; 2 card trays and 1 oversize folder; ca. 245 linear shelf feet) ca. 1965-1974, and contains papers pertaining to the political career of William B. Spong, Jr. (1920- ) of Portsmouth, Virginia, in the United States Senate, including campaign material, legislative files, speeches and news releases, correspondence, daily carbons, printed material, photographs, casework files, reel-to-reel tape recordings, videotape, constituent correspondence, research material, and bound volumes.
Decisions concerning the processing and retention of individual files were made by the Curator based upon the recommendations in Records Management Handbook for United States Senators and Their Repositories by Karen Dawley Paul, Archivist Senate Historical Office.
The first and largest series contains legislative files and are arranged alphabetically according to the Senate Committee System of the [then]seventeen standing committees with a small section based on legislation generated by special, select, & joint committees. These standing committees include: Aeronautical and Space Sciences; Agriculture and Forestry; Appropriations; Armed Services; Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs; Commerce; District of Columbia; Finance; Foreign Relations; Government Operations; Interior and Insular Affairs; Judiciary; Labor and Public Welfare; Post Office and Civil Service; Public Works; Rules and Administration; and Veteran's Affairs.
Spong served on the following committees and subcommittees:
1967-1968
Committee on Banking & Currency: Subcommittees on International Finance, Production: Stabilization, Securities, Small Business.
Committee on the District of Columbia - Fiscal Affairs (Chairman).
Committee on Public Works: Subcommittees on Air & Water Pollution, Pubic Roads, Special Subcommittee on Economic Development.
1969-1970
Committee on Commerce: Subcommittees on Consumer Engergy: Natural Resources & the Environment, Merchant Marine.
Committee on the District of Columbia - Fiscal Affairs: Subcommittee on Public Health, Education, & Safety (Chairman).
Committee on Public Works: Subcommittees on Air & Water Pollution, Public Roads, Special Subcommittee on Economic Development.
1971-1972
Committee on Commerce: Subcommittees on Aviation, Consumer, Environment, Merchant Marine, Oceans & Atmosphere.
Committee on Foreign Relations: Subcommittees on European Affairs, Oceans: International Environment, Western Hemisphere Affairs.
Select Committee on Equal Education Opportunities.
Select Committee on Standards & Conduct.
Each committee has a file at the beginning with more general correspondence before the files with subheadings which warrant a separate folder. Many of the files with subheadings often have related and earlier material in the general files so it is best to also consult these to make sure no material pertaining to a research topic is missed. The legislative files contain a mixture of constituent correspondence, correspondence with fellow legislators and legislative research material and memoranda.
The second series consists of the federal files containing files pertaining to the various federal departments, agencies, boards, and commissions which make up the major components of the Executive Branch of the Government. This series contains a mixture of correspondence from representatives of government agencies, constituents, and other legislators. There are also two much smaller subseries of independent agencies of the Judicial Branch and the Legislative Branch, including the Supreme Court, Tax Court, General Accounting Office, Government Printing Office, Library of Congress, etc.
The third series contains general files pertaining to the state of Virginia, Virginia and national politics, administrative office files, files pertaining to public activities such as awards, chairmanships and memberships, public relations files, and campaign files for both 1966 and 1972 (for additional files on these campaigns see the guide for 9838-b). Lists of notable correspondents from several of these folders include:
National Politics: Spiro T. Agnew (1968 Dec 17); Daniel B. Brewster (1968 Dec 4); W.C. "Dan" Daniel (1969 Jan 30); Thomas N. Downing (1969 Jan 22); Hubert H. Humphrey (1972 Jan 6); Lyndon B. Johnson (1969 Jan 17); George McGovern (1969 Jan 17; 1971 Dec 23); Walter Mondale (1968 Oct 18); Frank E. Moss (1971 Jan 7); James R. Shepley, Time(1967 Dec 11).
National Politics - Committee Assignments: John O. Marsh, Jr. (1971 Feb 2); Jennings Randolph (1971 Feb 8); Stuart Symington (1971 Jan 30); Ambassador H.G. Torbert, Jr. (1971 Feb 12); and George M. Warren, Jr. (1971 Jan 26).
National Politics - Democratic Convention: William M. Abbitt (1968 Jul 8); John B. Criswell (1968 Apr 18); Abe Ribicoff (1968 Sep 9); and Stanley C. Walker (1968 Aug 9).
National Politics - Democratic Senatorial Committee: Bill Chappell (1969 Jul 11); Frank N. Hoffman, Executive Director (1969 Oct 1; 1971 Jun 11); and Daniel K. Inouye (1969 Mar 12).
National Politics - Hubert H. Humphrey: Muriel Humphrey (1968 Sep 16)
National Politics - 1968 Presidential Election: W.M. Abbitt, W.C. "Dan" Daniel, John O. Marsh, Jr., and Edmund S. Muskie (clipped together 1968 Nov 15); and Walter Mondale (1968 May 22).
Public Activities - Invitations Accepted: Henry Bellman (1971 Feb 4); Thomas J. Bliley, Jr. (1971 Jan 29); Harry F. Byrd, Jr. (1971 Feb 8, Apr 12); Clifford P. Case (1971 Jan 27); Lawton Chiles (1971 May 26); Frank Church (1971 Feb 12, 22); William E. Fears (1972 Feb 12); Albert Gore (1971 Jul 22); Mark O. Hatfield (1971 May 4); Ernest F. Hollings (1971 Apr 28, Jul 29, Nov 4; 1972 Feb 10, 16); Harold C. Hughes (1971 May 21); Hubert H. Humphrey (1971 Nov 4); Daniel K. Inouye (1972 May 16); Henry M. Jackson (1971 Jan 27, Feb 19, Mar 10 & 29); Jacob K. Javits (1971 Nov 3); B. Everett Jordan (1971 Jan 19; 1972 Apr 18); George N. McMath (1972 Feb 14); Warren G. Magnuson (1971 Feb 19); Mike Mansfield (1971 Mar 9); Admiral Tom H. Moorer (1972 Mar 21); Frank E. Moss (1971 May 13); Gaylord Nelson (1971 Mar 9); Bob Packwood (1971 Feb 4); Jennings Randolph (1972 Jun 19, 21); Abe Ribicoff (1971 Mar 12); Admiral H.G. Rickover (1971 Nov 3); David E. Satterfield III (1971 Mar 18; 1972 May 8); William B. Scott (1971 Jun 10); Stuart Symington (1971 Nov 30); Daniel G. Van Clief (1971 Jul 16); G. William Whitehurst (1971 Sep 3).
Public Activities - Speakers: Edward W. Brooke (1968 Feb 21); John H. Chafee (1969 Apr 7); Alan A. Diamonstein (1969 Apr 7); Albert Gore (1968 May 15); Hubert H. Humphrey (1970 Mar 5); Walter F. Mondale (1968 Apr 18); Dean Rusk (1970 Feb 8); Stuart Symington (1969 Feb 10); Stewart L. Udall (1968 Feb 19); John A. Volpe (1969 Mar 7, attached to Mar 18); G. William Whitehurst (1970 Mar 16).
Public Relations - Speeches includes press/news releases, statements, excerpts from The Congressional Record, texts of Spong's speeches, announcements, and interviews. For an alphabetical index to the topics of Spong's speeches by year see Box 195.
State Politics includes: W.M. Abbitt (1970 Nov 5); George S. Aldhizer II (1972 Jan 13);George E. Allen, Jr. (1969 Jul 24); Carl E. Bain (1972 Jan 12); Robert F. Baldwin (1967 Aug 9); Armistead Boothe (1968 Dec 9); Adelard L. Brault (1968 Feb 7); Thomas P. Bryan (1969 Jul 24); C. William Cleaton (1971 Feb 12); John Warren Cooke (1972 Jan 12); W.C. "Dan" Daniel (1970 Nov 6); Thomas N. Downing (1970 Nov 5); William B. Dudley (1972 Jan 13); William R. Durland (1967 Nov 22); financial disclosure (1970 scattered); Marion G. Galland (1969 Mar 11); Joseph V. Gartlan, Jr. (1972 Jan 13); Duncan C. Gibb (1972 Jan 13); Mills E. Godwin (1967 Oct 10); Edward M. Holland (1972 Jan 13); Linwood Holton (1970 Mar 25); Flournoy L. Largent, Jr. (1970 Nov 27); George N. McMath (1972 Jan 12); J. Harry Michael, Jr. (1972 Feb 9); Andrew P. Miller (1967 Mar 8, Aug 24); Francis Pickens Miller (1968 Feb 15); Herbert N. Morgan (1972 Jan 13); Philip B. Morris (1972 Jan 12); Lucas D. Phillips (1969 Jul 23); Richard H. Poff (1972 Jan 12); William V. Rawlings (1968 Feb 5, 27); J. Sargent Reynolds (1969 Jul 24); Arthur H. Richardson (1969 Jul 25); J. Kenneth Robinson (1970 Nov 9); George Green Shackelford (analysis of the upcoming 1969 Governor's Race, 1967 Sep 28); Adlai E. Stevenson III (1970 Nov 11); David A. Sutherland (1972 Jan 13); William Carrington Thompson (1968 Jan 18); Lawrence Douglas Wilder (1969 Dec 5); Carrington Williams (1969 Dec 2); Murat W. Williams (1968 Dec 10).
The last group of files in the third series is entitled " VIP Correspondence." This designation was created by the staff of Special Collections to preserve letters from notable correspondents in files not otherwise deemed of permanent historical value and was not part of the original arrangement. These letters were culled from files such as courtesy, congratulations, gifts, greetings, and requests. For lists of these correspondents please see the folder listing for Cubic 162 at the end of the guide. The term "notable correspondent" in this case was limited to those individuals chiefly involved with politics and government.
Daily carbons ("yellows") of the correspondence of Senator Spong's office comprises the fourth series of files, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent by the years 1967- 1970, 1971, and 1972. The last and fifth series consists of such miscellaneous material as reel-to-reel tape recordings, video tape, oversize items, and two boxes of 5 x 8 index card files. One box of 5 x 8 cards is the alphabetical by year topical index to Spong's speeches, statements, and press releases, which are arranged in chronological order under the heading Public Relations - Speeches in the third series. The other box of cards appears to be an index to legislation and amendments introduced in Congress during 1974-1976.
Organization
The collection is arranged in five series based upon the original order imposed by Spong's office staff with the addition of two series at the end for the daily carbons and miscellaneous materials. The folders are generally in reverse chronological order except for the speeches and press releases in the General Series. The Ivystax box numbers are included in the folder listing with the box numbers. The series are:
Series I: Legislative Files (Boxes 1-90) including:
Senate Special, Select, & Joint Committees (Boxes 89-90)
Legislative Bills & Summaries (Box 90)
Series II: Federal Files
Subseries A: Executive Branch (Boxes 91-131)
Subseries B: Judicial Branch (Box 132)
Subseries C: Legislative Branch (Box 132)
Subseries D: Casework Files (Boxes 132- 139)
Series III: General Files (Boxes 140-162)
Series IV: Daily Carbons ["Yellows"] (Boxes 162-194)
Series V: Miscellaneous Material (Boxes 195-196)
Contents List
- Legislative
  - Aeronautical and Space Sciences 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - Aeronautical and Space Sciences - Appropriations 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Aeronautical and Space Sciences - Space Shuttle 1972 (Box 1)
  - Aeronautical and Space Sciences - Synchrocyclotron 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry 1966-1972, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Agricultural Act of 1968 (S.3590) 1968 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Agricultural Conservation Program 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Appropriations 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Community Development District Bill (S.645) 1967 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Consumer Agricultural Food Protection Act (S.2203) 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Dairy 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Farm Credit Act (S. 1483) 1971 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Farm Diversion Payments (Farm Subsidies) 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Food Stamps 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Food Stamps - Eligibility of Strikers 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Meat Inspection 1967 & 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 1(cont.))
  - Agriculture and Forestry - National Timber Supply Act (S.1832) 1969-1970 (Box 1(cont.))
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Peanuts 1968 (Box 1(cont.))
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Pesticides 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 1(cont.))
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Poultry (S.2932) and Egg (S.2116) Bills 1968 & 1970 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Production, Marketing and Stabilization of Prices 1967 & 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Rural Development Act 1972 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Rural Electrification Act and Telephone Bank Bill 1966-1967 & 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - School Lunch Program 1968-1972, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - School Lunch Questionnaire 1969, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Sugar Act Amendment Bill 1971 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Tobacco 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Agriculture and Forestry - Watershed Projects and Appropriations 1967-1968f (Box 2)
  - Appropriations 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Agriculture 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Agriculture - Laboratory Animal Welfare Act 1967 (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Defense 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - District of Columbia 1967 (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Education Bills 1971 (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Foreign Relations 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Health, Education, & Welfare 1967-1971, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Independent Offices 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Appropriations - Interior 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - Miscellaneous 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - National Aeronautics and Space Administration 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - National Aeronautics and Space (Statement by John E. Naugle) 1968 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - Public Works 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - Super Sonic Transport (SST) 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - Transportation 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations - Treasury, Post Office & Executive Office 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Armed Services - Administrative Discharge Procedures 1972 (Box 3)
  - Armed Services - Amnesty 1971 Dec-1972, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Armed Services - Anheuser Busch Company Property Exchange 1970 (Box 3)
  - Armed Services - Anti-Ballistic Missile System 1967-1969 Jul, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Armed Services - Anti-Ballistic Missile System 1969 Aug-1971, 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Anti-Ballistic Missile System Alphabetical File A-Z 1969, 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Anti-Ballistic Missile System (Out of State Correspondence) A-W 1969, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Appropriations 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Benefits 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Chemical & Biological Warfare 1969 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Civilian Casualties 1970 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Coast Guard Reserve Training 1970 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Culebra, Puerto Rico (Shelling by the Navy) 1970 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Defense Production Act Amendment (S. 3302) 1970 (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Draft Deferments & Exemptions 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Armed Services - Draft, Petitions to Repeal ca. 1971, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Judge Advocate Corps 1969-1971 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Mansfield Amendment 1971 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Military Construction 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Military Housing 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - National Guard 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - National Guard Technicians 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Pay 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Post Exchanges 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Procurement 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Reserve Officers' Training Corps 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Retirement Recomputation 1967-1970 Aug, 15 folders (Box 5)
  - Armed Services - Retirement Recomputation 1970 Sep-1972, 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Selective Service 1967-1972, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Selective Service - Research 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Survivors Benefits 1970-1972, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Tanker Construction 1971 (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Uniform Code of Military Justice 1971 (Box 6)
  - Armed Services - Volunteer Army 1971-1972, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Banking and Currency 1967-1971, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Banking and Currency - American Bankers' Association Positions on Legislation 1967-1968 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Balance of Payments Bill 1968, S.3218 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Bank Holding Company Bill (S.2569) 1969-1970, 9 folders (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Corporate Takeover Bids Full Disclosure (S. 510) 1967 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Credit Cards 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Credit Information Disclosure 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Credit Unions 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Economic Stabilization Act (S. 2891 & H.R. 11309) 1971 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Eisenhower Silver Dollar 1969 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Executive Sessions 1968 Jun (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Export/Import Bank 1967-1968, n.d., 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Fair Credit Billing Act (S. 652) 1971 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Fair Trade Reporting Act 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Federal Savings Institution Bill (H.R. 13718) 1968 (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Financial Institutions (chiefly S.1306), including reports re bank underwriting of bonds 1966-1972, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Banking and Currency - Financial Institutions - Investment Company Amendments (S. 1659) 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Financial Institutions - Investment Company Amendments (S.1659), Statements Before the Committee 1967, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Financial Institutions - The Savings and Loan Holding Company Amendments (S. 1542) 1967 (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Flood Insurance Act (S. 1985) 1967 (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Gold Cover (Removal) 1968, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs 1967-1972, 14 folders (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs - Fair Housing 1967 (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs - Interest Ceilings (S. 3133) 1967-1968 (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs - Mortgage Credit 1967 (Box 8)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs - Real Estate Settlement Fees 1972, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Housing and Urban Affairs Subcommittee Executive Session Agenda 1967 Oct (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Interest Rates 1967-1971 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - International Center Report (District of Columbia) 1969 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - International Finance 1967-1971 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Interstate Land Sales Full Disclosure Act (S. 275) 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Lockheed Loan 1971, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Martin Luther King Half Dollar 1968 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Public Transit Authorities Charter Bus Subsidies (H.R.. 10924) 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Savings and Loan Holding Company Act (S. 1542) 1967 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Securities 1971 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Securities - Mutual Funds. SEE ALSO: Financial Institutions - Investment Company Amendments 1967-1970, 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Securities - Mutual Funds (Out of State Correspondence) 1967 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Silver Certificates (S. 1352) 1967 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Small Business Administration 1967-1972 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Small Business Administration Amendment (S. 1862) 1967 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Small Business Administration - Crime Protection Insurance Bill 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Speeches by Spong [1968 ?] (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Truth-in-Lending Bill (S.5) 1967-1970, 4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Banking and Currency - Truth-in-Lending Bill (S.5) - Hearings re Revolving Credit Provisions 1967, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Banking and Currency - Truth-in-Lending Bill (S.5) - House Version 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Banking and Currency - Truth-in-Lending Bill (S.5) - Statements Before the Committee 1967 Jun (Box 10)
  - Banking and Currency - Uniform Accounting Procedures for Defense Contractors (S. 3097 & H.R. 17268) 1968 (Box 10)
  - Banking and Currency - Urban Insurance Bill (S.3028) 1968 (Box 10)
  - Commerce 1967-1972, 10 folders (Box 10)
  - Commerce - Alcohol and Tobacco - Alcohol Advertising 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Commerce - Alcohol and Tobacco - Cigarette Advertising 1967-1970, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Commerce - Alcohol and Tobacco - Cigarette Advertising 1972, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Animal Welfare 1967-1972, 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Animal Welfare - Anti-poisoning Act (S. 2083 & S. 2084) 1971 (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Animal Welfare - Wild Horses, S. 78 & H.R. 5060 1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Aviation 1967-1972, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Airport Authority Bill (S. 3128) 1971 (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Airport Development Act 1968 (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Airports & Airways 1969, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Airports & Airways 1970-1971, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Airports & Airways - Dulles Rapid Transit 1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Air Traffic Controllers 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Fare Discounts for Seniors (S. 1808) 1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Smoking on Airlines (S. 3255) 1970 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Aviation - Washington Metro Airport Authority 1969-1972, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Boxcar Shortage Subcommittee 1970-1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Campaign Spending Control Bills (S. 1, S. 382, S. 956) 1971 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications 1967-1972, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - AM/FM Radios 1968 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - Campaign Broadcasting Act 1970 & 1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - Film Classification (S.Res. 9) 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - Public Broadcasting 1967-1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - Renewal Licenses, S. 2004 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - T.V. Violence 1967-1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Communications - Unsolicited Calls 1972 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Consumer 1967-1969, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Commerce - Consumer 1970-1972, 9 folders (Box 13)
  - Commerce - Consumer - Auto Insurance Reform 1970-1972 (Box 13)
  - Commerce - Consumer - Class Action 1970-1971, 3 folders (Box 13)